<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Queenscript Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Musings on technology, development, javascript, and all in between]]></description><link>https://queenscript.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 19:54:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Web Builders 101 | Intro]]></title><description><![CDATA[Developers engineered the CMS interfaces to be easily usable by any user, most likely with the standards outlined by Usability.gov.  As a…]]></description><link>https://queenscript.com/web-builders-101/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://queenscript.com/web-builders-101/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Developers engineered the CMS interfaces to be easily usable by any user, most likely with the standards outlined by Usability.gov.  As a web designer, it is important to have a high-level understanding of how some of the most popular content management system works, and why some might be more important than others according to users’ particular needs.
As a web designer for a SAAS startup company, I am often working with multiple content management systems, and analyzing their importances.
Outlined below, I have compare some of the top three popular CMS’s on the net- Wordpress, Squarespace and Wix, and have made my own audit of why each come with their own share of pros and cons, that make it worthwhile from a personal, business, and client-facing perspective. The goal is to choose the best platform for our work, as well as the work for our clients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;WIX&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;USABILITY | What is this CMS good for?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to simple customizations, Wix is the best CMS for the job. The drag and drop features allow users to easily customize their site from the colors, to the shapes. The code integration are also seemless, and makes making code changes on this site very powerful. Wix is a WYSIWYG, and open HTML abilities to make customizations similar to WP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEO | How does this CMS help build more website traffic?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wix has a robus offering of add-ons, which this CMS calls “widgets,” it’s also known as plugins on Wordpress. Popular widgets like Rabbit SEO are provided on the Wix app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PRICE  | Is it worth the cost?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$15/month increases depending on additional services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FINAL THOUGHT  | How does this CMS accomplish business goals?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Square-Press Combo” - easy  to navigate and edit website with no experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;SQUARESPACE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;USABILITY | What is this CMS good for?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WYSIWYG- you may add content by clicking on a dropdown of  additional “containers” for content such as text, images, videos, basic HTML. While it’s a popular option, it’s the least customizable &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEO | How does this CMS help build more website traffic?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t have an SEO specific app, but has built-in responsiveness (i.e. mobile, tablet, multi-browser use). Google recently updated their technology to give mobile-optimized sites a higher priority&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PRICE  | Is it worth the cost?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$18/month, charged annually for business accounts, there are additional costs for an ecommerce store &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FINAL THOUGHT  | How does this CMS accomplish business goals?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trendiest web templates- mobile responsiveness is what makes this option so popular amongst a wide array of startups and small businesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;WORDPRESS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;USABILITY | What is this CMS good for?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offers the largest array of website layouts. There is a challenge with navigating and using plugins
(the extra functionality sometimes comes at extra time and money). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SEO | How does this CMS help build more website traffic?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has a robust library for SEO plugins. Over 28% of all websites on the internet are powered by WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;PRICE  | Is it worth the cost?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$0 + hosting costs, some templates range from $15-$50 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FINAL THOUGHT  | How does this CMS accomplish business goals?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheapest and most customizable option- corporate favorite because it allows you to build your brand’s” truest web form”.
Take the Quiz Below to Test Your Knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 100vh; overflow: hidden;&quot; src=&quot;https://queenshabazz.github.io/quizapp/&quot; &gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[SEO 101]]></title><description><![CDATA[What Does SEO Stand For? SEO is an acronym, which stands for Search Engine Optimization. SEO is essentially all about making a website…]]></description><link>https://queenscript.com/seo/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://queenscript.com/seo/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Does SEO Stand For?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEO is an acronym, which stands for Search Engine Optimization. SEO is essentially all about making a website better to be read and found by search engines. You might be wondering, what does it mean to be optimized for search engines? The answer to this critical question of being search engine optimized is shared with many entrepreneurs and small businesses alike. The major search engines on the internet include Google, Bing, and Yahoo. However, when SEO professionals talk about what it means to be search engine optimized, they are usually referring to a website’s performance as assessed by Google.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Is SEO Important?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Google’s Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Starter Guide, “Search engine optimization (SEO) is often about making small modifications to parts of your website… which could have a noticeable impact on your site’s user experience and performance in organic search results. ” Essentially SEO is all about the way a website is built, and its performance and ability to be found on the web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Does SEO Work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the key terms around SEO include: index, crawler, and the Googlebot. The index of a website can understood as storage. The index is where Google and the other search engines store information about your website’s web pages, and describes the content, as well as URL address of each page on the website. Google essentially finds each page on your website, reads through the process of crawling, and adds it to the index that is displayed in search results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think About Building a Strong SEO Practice &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crawling process supports displaying information to users about their search. Google and other search engines look for web pages that are new or updates, and add them to the search index. Having a website that is SEO friendly is crucial in being found on the web. As the internet grows larger with more content added to it, literally every second, it is important for small businesses, and entrepreneurs alike to know how to stand out amongst the crowd. Adding keywords, making sure that the site is accessible to screen readers, and building a fast performing site are all part of having a strong SEO strategy for your website.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Top 3 SEO Tips]]></title><description><![CDATA[Website traffic deals with how often, how frequent, and how long users are visiting. Such digital traffic is an indicator to how well your…]]></description><link>https://queenscript.com/seo-tips/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://queenscript.com/seo-tips/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Website traffic deals with how often, how frequent, and how long users are visiting. Such digital traffic is an indicator to how well your business is doing on the web. It is also a good measure for your marketing efforts, and ultimately supports lead generation. Website traffic will also allow services like Google Analytics to measure your website’s performance when users enter your site, including calculating bounce rates and exit rates, to help you determine what content works well for your customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Not All Web Traffic Is Created Equal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main streams to generate traffic: free and paid. The traffic on your website supports Search Engine Optimization (SEO), by helping increase your rank in the search index. Essentially, the more users searching for your website, and entering your website, the higher on the list you will be ranked when a user searches for sites like yours in a search engine like Google.com. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;From Traffic to Engagement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s one particular caveat to this digital traffic paradigm, however. Engagement on your site is just as important as the traffic to your site. If you have a high bounce rate (meaning many users might land on your site, but immediately close out the window and do not revisit your site), this will have a negative impact on your SEO. Ways to increase conversion into better conversion is to include buttons with call to actions, forms that capture leads in the right parts of your site, and making a usable navigation that will allow users to get to the information they need, seamlessly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Top 3 Channels You Can Leverage to Build More Web Traffic, Engagement, For Free&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many ways to approach increasing your website’s traffic and engagement. Often, there is not a one-size-fits-all approach, because it is heavily driven by your industry, the customers in your industry, and the way information is accessed and delivered in your industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Email is a channel that can support increased traffic and engagement.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newsletters are a commonly used way that businesses engage with customers, outside of their own websites. Links to your website and call to actions in the body of your emails are tools that drive users back to your site, where they will more likely be engaged with the content that they “previewed” in the body of the newsletter you shared with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to email, social media can support directing your customers back to your site with the content that you share. Social media is a different digital “hang out” spot, where users are often consuming multiple streams of content and information. Your social media strategy should have awareness on engagement trends by platform- how you engage with your customers on Facebook should be different to how you communicate with them on Instagram, and how you share information on Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, blogging is a great middle ground between email and social media. Blogs hold a lot of information  is a great way to share information that your customers are seeking, while also promoting your website. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>